Guide to the New World Writing Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
New World Writing records
1952-1960
YCAL MSS 388
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
22.32
(54 boxes)
The collection documents all aspects of the production and promotion of the literary magazine New World Writing from its first issue in 1952 to its last issue in 1959. Correspondence, including letters by and about various authors whose work was published in the magazine, and manuscripts, including corrected typescripts of published works, shed light on the selection and editorial process. Highlights include the corrected typescript of "Catch-18" by Joseph Heller, originally published in issue #7, which became the first chapter of Catch-22. Files of the executive editor, Arabel J. Porter, and the promotion department variously document the work involved in producing and publicizing individual issues, while files of comments, reviews, and clippings document how the magaine was received. Also found are files relating to some of the more general business of the magazine.
New World Writing
Porter, Arabel J.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of New American Library, 1959.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
New World Writing (1952-1959)
New World Writing was a literary magazine published by New American Library between 1952 and 1959, and edited by Arabel J. Porter et al. Modeled in part on Penguin New Writing, published in England from 1940-1950 and edited by John Lehmann, the magazine was intended to bring "an important and representative cross section of current literature and criticism" (Issue #1) to a widespread audience. New World Writing was published in fifteen biannual issues and featured works of fiction, drama, essays, and poetry by new and leading writers from around the world. Contributors included Gore Vidal, Flannery O'Connor, Jack Kerouac, W. H. Auden, James Baldwin, Samuel Beckett, Saul Bellow, Jorge Luis Borges, Bertolt Brecht, E. E. Cummings, Jean Genet, André Gide, Christopher Isherwood, Norman Mailer, Pablo Picasso, Kenneth Rexroth, William Carlos Williams, Upton Sinclair, Wallace Stevens, Eugène Ionesco, Octavio Paz and Tennessee Williams.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents all aspects of the production and promotion of the literary magazine New World Writing from its first issue in 1952 to its last issue in 1959. Correspondence, including letters by and about various authors whose work was published in the magazine, and manuscripts, including corrected typescripts of published works, shed light on the selection and editorial process. Highlights include the corrected typescript of "Catch-18" by Joseph Heller, originally published in issue #7, which became the first chapter of Catch-22. Files of the executive editor, Arabel J. Porter, and the promotion department variously document the work involved in producing and publicizing individual issues, while files of comments, reviews, and clippings document how the magaine was received. Also found are files relating to some of the more general business of the magazine.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1952-1960. II. Manuscripts, 1952-1959. III. Galley Proofs, 1952-1959. IV. Editorial and Publicity Files, 1952-1959. V. General Business Files, 1952-1959. VI. Clippings and Foreign Reviews Files, 1952-1960.
New world writing; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors and publishers -- United States; Editors -- United States; Literature -- Periodicals; Literature, Modern -- 20th Century; Little magazines -- United States; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Editors; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Baldwin, James, 1924-1987; Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989; Bellow, Saul, 1915-2005; Borges, Jorge Luis, 1899-1986; Brecht, Bertolt, 1898-1956; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Genet, Jean, 1910-1986; Gide, André, 1869-1951; Heller, Joseph ( Catch-22); Ionesco, Eugène, 1912-1994; Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986; Kerouac, Jack, 1922-1969; Mailer, Norman, 1923-2007; O'Connor, Flannery, 1925-1964; Paz, Octavio, 1914-1998; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Porter, Arabel J.; Rexroth, Kenneth, 1905-1982; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968; Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955; Vidal, Gore, 1925-2012; Williams, Tennessee, 1911-1983; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963
- Correspondence, 1952-1960; Series I; 8.6; (21 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subseries: Literary Correspondence and Agent and Publisher Correspondence. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence with authors, translators, agents, and publishers, as well as interoffice correspondence, regarding the selection and inclusion of works in New World Writing magazine. Many files contain correspondence about the individual listed, rather than letters by that person.
  - Literary Correspondence, 1952-1959
    - "A" General, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abel, Lionel, translator (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abse, Dannie (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adamov, Arthur (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aichinger, Ilse (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alexander, Anthony (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aldridge, John W. (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Algren, Nelson (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allen, Gay Wilson, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Allen, Gregory (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Allen, Walter (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alvarez, Alfred (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Alvaro, Corrado (Issue #2). Translated by Frances Keene, circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Amaral, José Vinicius Vieira do (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14-18)
    - Amen, G. C. (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Anderson, Lee, 1954, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Anderson, Patrick (Issue #16), circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Andraide, Carlos Drummond De (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Aney, Edith T. and Karell, Sven O, translators (Issue #8), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Arnér, Sivar (Issue #8)
    - Antonov, Sergei (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Armstrong, Louis (Issue #6), circa 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Arnér, Sivar (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ashbery, John (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Atik, Leah (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arreola, Juan José (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Auchincloss, Louis (Issues #1 and #3), circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh) (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bail, Everett (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Baldwin, James (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bandiera, Manuel (Issues #7 and #14), circa 1955, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Barker, George (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Baro, Gene (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bazin, Hervé, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Beckett, Samuel (Issues #5 and #10), circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Beigel, Uli (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bell, Charles (Issues #1 and #5), circa 1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Bellow, Saul (Issues #6 and #12), circa 1954, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Benn, Gottfried (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Bennett, Peggy (Issues #3 and #8), circa 1953, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Bentley, Nelson (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bercovici, Eric (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Berger, Thomas (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Berne, Stanley (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 47-48)
    - Berriault, Gina (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Berto, Giuseppe (Issue #1). Translated by Ben Johnson, circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Bey, Hamdi (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bishop, Leonard (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Blackburn, Paul (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Blaustein, Alfred (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Blazer, Samuel (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Bloom, Robert (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Bluestone, George (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Bly, Robert (Issue #11 and #15), circa 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Boland, Patrick (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Boll, Heinrich (Issue #7). Translated by Guy Bishop, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Booth, Phillip (Issue #9 and #10), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis (Issue #4 and #14), circa 1953, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Bosch, Juan (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Bowles, Patrick, 1954, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Branner, H. C. (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Brecht, Bertolt (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Breit, Harvey (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Brinnin, John Malcolm (Issues #1, #3, and #5), circa 1952, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Brockway, Wallace (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Brown, Spencer (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Brower, Brock (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Broyard, Anatole (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Brunson, Beverly (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Budlong, Paula (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Bullock, Michael. Translator, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Burr, Gray, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Busta, Christine (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Butler, Clare (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Butler, Guy (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Calisher, Hortense (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Candido, Anthony (Issue #13), circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Caldwell, Erskine (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Cantwell, Robert (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Carpenter, A. (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Carreño, José Suárez (Issue #3). Translated by Anthony Kerrigan, circa 1953 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Carunungan, Celso Al (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Cassill, R. V. (Ronald Verlin), (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Cela, Camilo José, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Chang, Dana (Issue #9), circa 1959 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Chapman, Kenneth, translator of Tarjei Vesaas (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Chilver, Sally (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Chubak, Ṣadiq (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Chumacero, Alí, (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Ciardi, John (Issues #9 and #15), circa 1956, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Clark, Austin (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Clancy, Joseph P., 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Clay, George R. (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Coggeshall, Helen (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Cogswell, Fred (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Collins, Lucinda (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Connell, Evan S., Jr. (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Cooke, Dorian (Issues #7 and #11), circa 1955, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Cooper, Jane (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Corke, Hilary (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Cortázar, Julio (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Coulette, Henri (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Court, Artelia Browne (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Cronin, Anthony (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Curnow, Allen (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Currie, Ellen (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Dagerman, Stig (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - De Lima, Jorge (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - De Onís, Harriet, translator (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 5, Folder 116-117)
    - Delius, Anthony (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Del Río, Angel, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Demarest, Donald (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Dempsey, David (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Denny, Reuel (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Dennis, Alice (Weshke) (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Devlin, Dennis (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Diamond, Sidney (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Drake, Carol Christopher (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Duffield, Edward D. (Edward Dickinson) (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Dull, Kenneth (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Duke, Osborn (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Dumur, Guy (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Duncan, Harry (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Eastlake, William (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Eberhart, Richard (Issues #2, #3, #5, and #6), circa 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 133-134)
    - Ekelöf, Gunnar (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Eich, Günter (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Eliot, Alexander (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Elliot, George P. (Issue #13), circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Ellison, James Whitfield (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Ellison, Ralph (Issues #4 and #9), circa 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Engel, Monroe (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Eskie, Bruno (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Evans, Oliver (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Fallon, Padraic (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Farrell, James T. (James Thomas) (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 145-146)
    - Farren, Robert (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Feibleman, Peter S. (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Fenton, Charles A. (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Fey, Isabella (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Figueredo, Álvaro (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Fitts, Dudley (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Florit, Eugenio (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Foote, Shelby (Issues #1 and #4), circa 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Forni, Luigi (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Fraser, G. S. (George Sutherland) (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Fremantle, Anne Jackson (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Friar, Kimon (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Friedberg, Gertrude (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Friend, Robert (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Fuller, Roy (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Fuyuhiko, Kitagawa, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Gaddis, William (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Gallegos, Romero (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - García Lorca, Federico (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Gardner, Isabelle (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Garrett, George (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Garrigue, Jean (Issues #4, #10, and #12), circa 1953-1957 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Genet, Jean, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Ghana Selections. James Moxon and James Miller. (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 7, Folder 171-172)
    - Ghiselin, Brewster (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Gide, André (Issue #9). Translated by Patrick Gregory, circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Glanville, Brian (Issue #6), circa 1954 (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Glaze, Andrew (Issues #4 and #9), circa 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Gold, Herbert (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 7, Folder 177-178)
    - Gold, Ivan (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Goldknopf, David (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - González, José Luis (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Goodwin, John (Issue #2), circa1952 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Gordimer, Nadine (Issues #2 and #4), circa 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Grant, Robert (Issues #1 and #15), circa 1952, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Granell, Eugenio Fernández (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Greacen, Robert (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Grau, Shirley Ann (Issues #4 and #10), circa 1953, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Graves, Robert (Issues #14 and #15), circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Gray, Camilla (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Gregor, Arthur (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Gregory, Horace (Issues #5, #7, #11, #12, and #14), circa 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Gregory, Patrick (Issues #12 and #15), circa 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Griffin, C. W. (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Griffin, Howard (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Griffin, John Howard (Issue #3 and #12), circa 1953, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Grossman, William L. (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph) (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Guillén, Jorge, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Gunn, Thom, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Hall, Carol (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Hall, Donald (Issues #5, #7 and #11), circa 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Hall, J. C. (John Clive) (Issues #1 and #7), circa 1952, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Hamburg, Michael (Issues #12 and #13), circa 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Hamilton, Horace E. (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Hamner, Earl (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Hansen, Martin (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Hards, Terence (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Harrison, John P. (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Hartley, Anthony (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Hasegawa, Saburo, 1954, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - Hazo, Samuel John (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 211)
    - Hecht, Roger (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - Heller, Joseph (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - Hemley, Cecil (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - Herman, Bonnie (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 215)
    - Hershberger, Ruth (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 216)
    - Herzing, Albert, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - Hewitt, John (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Hitchcock, Henry Russell and Philip C. Johnson (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - Hochman, Sandra (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 220)
    - Hoetis, Themistocles (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Hoffman, Daniel G. (Issues #8 and #13), circa 1955, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Holmes, John (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 9, Folder 223)
    - Howes, Barbara (Mrs. Wm. Jay Smith), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Humphries, Rolfe (Issues #1 and #8), circa 1952, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Hunter, Sam (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Hutchins, Patricia (Issues #8 and #11), circa 1955, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 227)
    - Hutson, Patricia (Issue #12), circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - Hyun, Peter (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Ishatow, David (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Inove, Mitsuko (Issue #6), circa 1954 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Ionesco, Eugène (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Ish, David Allen (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Ishikawa, Tatsuzo (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Isherwood, Christopher (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Jackson, James Turner (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Jackson, Shirley (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Jayakar, Pupul (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - Jennings, Elizabeth (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - Jones, James (Issues #2, #13 and #14), circa 1952, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - Jeffers, Robinson (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 242)
    - Josephs, Laurence (Issues #2 and #9), circa 1952, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - Justice, Donald Rodney (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - Kadish, Mortimer R. (Mortimer Raymond) (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Kallman, Chester (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - Katue, Kitasono (Issue #6), circa 1954 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - Kay, Ellen (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - Kemp, Lysander (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 250)
    - Keogh, Thomas (Issue #5), circa 1954 (Box 10, Folder 251)
    - Kerouac, Jack (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 252)
    - King, Jay Lee (Mrs. Peter King) (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Knobil, Henry (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Kinnell, Galway (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 255)
    - Kirsch, Robert R. (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Kolmor, Gertrud (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - Koning, Hans (Issue #8), circa 1955 (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - Krleza, Miroslav (Issue #11), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 259)
      See also: Cooke, Dorian (Issues #7 and #11)
    - Kunitz, Stanley (Issues #4 and #9), circa 1953, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 260)
    - Kurt, Kim (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 261)
    - Ladd, Gabrielle (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 262)
    - Lafollette, Melvin W. (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - Lall, Arthur S. (Arthur Samuel). (Issues #2 and #9), circa 1952, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 264)
    - Lamming, George (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 265)
    - Langer, Susanne Katherina Knauth (Issue #4), circa 1953 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Langland, Joseph (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 10, Folder 267)
    - Lapsley, Mary, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 268)
      See also: Prévert, Jacques (Issue #10)
    - Larkin, Philip (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 269)
    - Laughlin, Clarence John (Issue #15), circa 1959 (Box 11, Folder 270)
    - Laughlin, James (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 271)
    - Lawner, Lynne (Issue #10), circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 272)
    - Lax, Robert (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 11, Folder 273)
    - Layzer, Robert B. (Issues #9 and #11), circa 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 274)
    - Lebrun, Rico (Issue #14), circa 1958 (Box 11, Folder 275)
    - Lee, Alwyn (Issue #2), circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 276)
    - Lehmann, John (Issues #2 and #5), circa 1952-1954 (Box 11, Folder 277)
    - Lehmann, Rosamond, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 278)
    - Lehmann, Wilhelm (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 11, Folder 279)
    - Levine, Rosalind (Issue #9), circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 280)
    - Leyda, Jay (Issue #3), circa 1953 (Box 11, Folder 281)
    - Leydenfrost, Robert J. (Issue #7), circa 1955 (Box 11, Folder 282)
    - Lindegren, Erik (Issue #11), circa 1957 (Box 11, Folder 283)
    - Locke, Alain LeRoy (Issue #1), circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 284)
    - Loerke, Oskar (Issue #13), circa 1958 (Box 11, Folder 285)